字幕by: Hongjiang399
微信：Hongjiang399
这门《Java基本培训》目的是教你一些
This course, Java Essential Training is designed to teach you the basics of the
Java编程语言的基本概念。
Java programming language.
你可能会考虑这门课程是否适合你，本课程建议你
You might be asking yourself whether this is the right course for you, and here
考虑以下几个方面。
are some questions to ask.
首先，你想开发怎么样的软件？
First of all, what kind of software do you want to create?
Java可以用于多种应用软件的开发
Java is used to program a variety of applications.
你可以用Java来开发基于servlets、Java Server Pages (简称JSP)等
You can use Java to build Web-based dynamic applications using programming
此类编程模型的动态网页应用。
models known as servlets or Java Server Pages, also known as JSP.
Java也可以用来开发移动应用，例如应用于平板电脑和手机等
Java is also used to program mobile applications, that is, applications that are
移动平台的安卓、黑莓应用。
for the Android or BlackBerry mobile platforms, both phones and tablets.
还有很多其他类型的利用Java开发的应用
And there are many other types of applications you can build with Java, and I'll
我将会在以后的视频中提及。
explain some of these in later videos.
另外，Java跟很多其他语言是有区别的。
There are some things however that Java is not.
Java不是JavaScript
Java is not JavaScript.
JavaScript是与所有现代网页浏览器相结合的一门动态脚本语言
JavaScript is the dynamic scripting language that's incorporated into all modern
用于创建动态网页应用，其代码
Web browsers and is used to create dynamic applications where the application
能被浏览器直接运行
code is executed by the browser itself.
虽然Java和JavaScript都有"Java"字样，但它们是
Even though Java and JavaScript share the term Java, they are very
两门不同的语言
different languages.
在语法和外观方面它们有相似之处，但你运行它们的方式
They have some similarities in their syntax and appearance, but the way you use
以及它们内部的运行机制是有根本区别的。
them and the way they work internally is completely different.
如果你想要学习如何搭建动态网页，且其代码
So if your goal is to learn how to build dynamic webpages, where the code is
能够被浏览器直接运行，那么你需要学JavaScript
executed in the browser, you should be learning JavaScript.
另外Java并不能用于开发所有移动平台的应用
Java is also not used to build native mobile apps for all platforms.
它不能用于开发运用于iPhone和iPad等基于iOS系统
It isn't used to build native iOS applications that is applications for
的本地应用
the iPhone and iPad.
开发iOS应用你需学习Objective C语言以及Xcode开发软件
For that you should use Objective C and the Xcode IDE, and it's also not used to
Java也不能用于开发Windows Phone应用
build native Windows Phone applications.
Windows Phone是微软新开发的手机操作系统移动平台
Windows Phone is the operating system of the new phone platform from Microsoft.
那里的应用需要用到C#或VB .NET等语言以及
For those types of applications you should use either C# or VB.NET and some
Visual Studio开发环境
version of the Visual Studio environment.
有些人认为Java不是世界上最简单的语言
Some people think that Java isn't the easiest language in the world.
因其是一门编译型语言且具有严格的语法结构
It is a compiled language and it has very strict data typing rules.
另外，你还需要了解面向对象的编程，从而更好地应用Java
And in order to be effective in Java you need to understand something
开发应用，我将会在以后的课程中
about object-oriented programming, but I'll be teaching you all that
教会你这些
during this course.
从另一角度来看，Java同时也不是世界上
And the other thing that's true of Java is that it's not the most difficult
最难的语言
language in the world.
Java是一门具有高度一致性的语言
Java is an incredibly consistent language.
一旦你学会了Java的语言规则，一旦你学会了从语言的角度
Once you learn the rules of Java, once you learn how to think in the
思考问题，你将很快能够扩展你的应用工具以及
languages' terms you will find that you can extend your tools and your
你的编程能力
capabilities very, very quickly.
那么谁是本课程的目标学员呢？
So who is the target audience for this particular course?
本课程是针对那些想利用Java编程语言开发应用的任何人的
The course is designed for anybody who wants to build software using the Java
特别是针对其中已经对基本编程概念
programming language, but specifically it's designed for those who already have
有所了解的人
a basic programming vocabulary.
软件开发者们在交流的时候都有着他们都能理解的
Software developers as with many trades have their own unique vocabulary
一些独特的具体名词
incorporating terms that they all understand.
也许这些名词在不同编程语言中有不同的含义
Many of these terms have different meanings from one programming language to
但开发者们都能顺利交流
another, but programmers can talk to each other.
如果你不确定你是否理解了编程语言的基本名词
So if you are not sure whether you have that vocabulary already in place,
这有一个小测试
here is a little test.
你能回答以下问题吗？
Can you answer these questions?
你不一定要从Java的角度来回答，但你是否
You don't have to answer them in the context of Java, but can you answer these
能够简单引用其他编程语言来回答呢？
very simply in reference to any programming language?
首先，什么是编程语句？
First, what is a programming statement?
什么是变量？
What is a variable?
什么是函数？什么是条件或者逻辑条件？
What is a function, and what is a condition or a logical condition?
如果你能回答上述问题，那么你已经准备好了
If you can answer these questions then you are ready for this course.
我会展示如何利用Java语言来描述这些名词以及
I'll show you how these terms are used in Java and how they are implemented in
它们是怎么在这门特定语言中应用的
this particular programming language.
如果你不熟悉这些名词，且你之前没有学过任何一种编程语言
If these terms are foreign to you and you haven't worked with any programming
建议你先去学习这门课程：
languages before, you might first want to watch this course.
《编程的基础：入门篇》
Foundations of Programming: Fundamentals.
这门Lynda.com的课程可以解释清楚上述名词，以及向你展示
This Lynda.com course explains these terms and shows you how they are
它们如何在多种不同语言中应用，包括Java
implemented in a variety of programming languages, including Java;
学习了上述基本课程之后，你将完全为这门课程
and after you watch this course you'll be completely ready for Java
做好了准备
Essential Training.
对那些能够回答上述问题的人，或以前学过其他编程语言的人
For those who can answer those questions and who might have worked in at least
你将会发现用过某门编程语言
one previous programming language, you'll find that certain programming
将使你很容易学习Java语言
languages get you ready for Java more easily than others.
Java是一门C类型的语言，它的语法和基本句式看起来
Java is a C-Style language, that is, its syntax and basic appearance look very
很像C语言或者其他一些具有
much like the language C and there are a number of programming languages who
同样特征的编程语言
share these characteristics.
如果你曾用过这些语言的其中一门，那么你将很快能接受Java
If you've worked in any of these languages you'll recognize Java very, very quickly.
这些语言包含: C, C++, C#, JavaScript, 甚至PHP
They include C, C++, C#, JavaScript, and even PHP.
所有这些语言具有相同的基本语法，因此你将能够很快地
All of these languages share basic syntax rules, and you'll be able to adapt
把你已有的知识应用到Java上
your existing knowledge to Java very fast.
如果你曾用过句式上并不类似于Java的
If you've worked in any other languages those languages might not match the
某一门语言
basic appearance of Java.
这些语言可能包括Visual Basic, VB.NET或者ColdFusion开发者, ColdFusion
These might include Visual Basic or VB. NET or ColdFusion developers, ColdFusion
标志型语言，或者是汇编语言等等
Markup Language or Assembly language and many others.
如果你熟悉这些语言，或者是其他不类似于C语法类型的语言
If you know any of these languages or any others that don't share C-Style
你也可以进行本课程的学习，因为在课程中
syntax, you should still be ready for this course because along the way I am
我将会详细解释Java语法和Java概念，以及怎么应用
going to explain Java syntax and Java concepts, and how to use Java variables
Java语句、函数和条件逻辑
statements, functions, and conditional logic.
总之，只要你用过某一门编程语言，并且你能回答上述基本问题
As long as you've worked in some programming language and can answer those basic
那么你就已经准备好了
questions, you are ready.
现在让我们开始学习Java编程语言吧
So let's get started learning the Java programming language.
字幕GitHub: github.com/Hongjiang399/JavaEssentialTrainingSRT